{
  "questions": [
    {
      "answer": "Dr. No",
      "question": "Which among the following is the first James Bond movie?",
      "options": [
        "Dr. No",
        "Thunderball",
        "The spy who loved me",
        "Die another day"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Leaving Las Vegas",
      "question": "Nicolas Cage got his first Oscar award for which movie ?",
      "options": [
        "National Treasure",
        "Ghost Rider",
        "Arsenal",
        "Leaving Las Vegas"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Alan Turing",
      "question": "Benedict Cumberbatch played the role of which famous mathematician in the movie 'The Imitation Game' ?",
      "options": [
        "Paul Erdős",
        "Stephen Hawking",
        "Alan Turing",
        "Srinivasa Ramanujan"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Apollo 13",
      "question": "Which of the following space movies had the tagline 'Failure is not an option' ?",
      "options": [
        "The Martian",
        "Armageddon",
        "Apollo 13",
        "Mission to Mars"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Lucasfilm",
      "question": "The Motorola Droid smartphone licensed the branding 'Droid' from which film company ?",
      "options": [
        "Universal Pictures",
        "Lucasfilm",
        "Warner Bros",
        "Paramount Pictures"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Legends of the Fall",
      "question": "Which among the following movies is not related to World War 2 ?",
      "options": [
        "Saving Private Ryan",
        "The Great Escape",
        "Dunkirk",
        "Legends of the Fall"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Madeleine Stowe",
      "question": "Who played the character of the Cora Munro in the film 'The Last of the Mohicans' ?",
      "options": [
        "Madeleine Stowe",
        "Jodhi May",
        "Brooke Shields",
        "Mary Stuart Masterson"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Green Book",
      "question": "Which movie won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2019 ?",
      "options": [
        "Bohemian Rhapsody",
        "Black Panther",
        "Green Book",
        "The Shape of Water"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Chamber of Secrets",
      "question": "Tom Marvolo Riddle's diary was destroyed in which Harry Potter movie ?",
      "options": [
        "Goblet of Fire",
        "Chamber of Secrets",
        "Half-Blood Prince",
        "Prisoner of Azkaban"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Natasha Romanoff",
      "question": "Which of the following characters survived Thanos' snap in Avengers: Infinity War movie ?",
      "options": [
        "Peter Quill",
        "T'Challa",
        "Stephen Strange",
        "Natasha Romanoff"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which among the 4 is the longest running movie franchise,as of now,according to the Guiness World records itself ?",
      "options": [
        "James Bond series",
        "Marvel Franchise",
        "Godzilla",
        "Star wars series"
      ],
      "answer": "Godzilla"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which among these movies has spawned the most number of remakes?",
      "options": [
        "King Kong",
        "Seven Samurai",
        "Inavsion Of The Body Snatchers",
        "A Christmas Carol"
      ],
      "answer": "A Christmas Carol"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these  movies spawned a tv series as well?",
      "options": [
        "Twin Peaks",
        "Twilight Zone",
        "Mask",
        "Mission impossible"
      ],
      "answer": "Mask"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is the first popular movie to feature a surprise ending which overturns the entire film",
      "options": [
        "Citizen Kane",
        "The Cabinet of Dr Caligari",
        "Psycho",
        "Planet of the apes"
      ],
      "answer": "The Cabinet of Dr Caligari"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these movies have a plot twist ?",
      "options": [
        "Charade(1964)",
        "Sleuth",
        "Sixth Sense",
        "House of Games"
      ],
      "answer": "Sixth Sense"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which among the following is not  remake of a Bollywood movie",
      "options": [
        "A Common Man (2013)",
        "Sheep without a Shepherd (2020)",
        "Delivery Man (2013)",
        "Fear (1996)"
      ],
      "answer": "Sheep without a Shepherd (2020)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was the first actor to portray James Bond on screen?",
      "options": [
        "Barry Nelson",
        "Sean Connery",
        "Sir Roger Moore",
        "George Lazenby"
      ],
      "answer": "Barry Nelson"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who among the following has played the most number of roles in a single movie?",
      "options": [
        "Kamal Hassan-Dashavataram",
        "James McAvoy-Split",
        "Johnson George-Aaranu Njan",
        "Eddie Murphy-The Nutty Professor"
      ],
      "answer": "Johnson George-Aaranu Njan"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which slasher series among these added a new angle to the genre  by introducing irony and making the movie meta(self –referential) , in the 1990s?",
      "options": [
        "Nightmare on Elm street",
        "I know what you did last summer",
        "Scream",
        "Scary Movie"
      ],
      "answer": "Nightmare on Elm street"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who among the following is the first Indian actor to appear in  a Hollywood movie (significant role)?",
      "options": [
        "Shashi Kapoor",
        "Kabir Bedi",
        "Persis Khambatt",
        "Sabu Dastagir"
      ],
      "answer": "Sabu Dastagir"
    }
  ],
  "title": "Hollywood"
}